opposingviews.com 2013-05-13

# Privacy Policy

Effective August 1, 2012

This policy tells you how Opposing Views ("OV") collects, uses and protects your information. This policy does not cover how we treat personal information that is obtained through other sources, such as offline, on other websites or through e-mail communications. This policy also does not apply to the practices of companies that OV does not own or control or to people that OV does not employ or manage.

### 1\. What and How We Collect Personal Information

You can browse [www.opposingviews.com](http://www.opposingviews.com/), and any other affiliated Opposing Views owned or operated websites (the "Sites") without telling us who you are or revealing any personal information about yourself. Certain features of the Sites do require that you register and supply some information that enables us to identify you. When you register, we ask you for your e-mail address and a screen name and password that you create.

In order for us to provide content and advertising that is targeted to your interests we may ask you for, and you may choose to (or choose not to) provide us with demographic information such as your gender, age, location, income level, educational level and other personal characteristics such as your political, religious and other beliefs. Providing any of this information is optional.

We do NOT ask for governmental identification numbers, credit card numbers or other financial account identifying numbers, codes or passwords. If you receive an e-mail or any request for this type of information please notify us at once at [legal@opposingviews.com](mailto:legal@opposingviews.com).

We also collect some information automatically from your computer while you use the Sites including your IP address, computer and connection information, browser type and version, operating system, platform, the URLs you came from and go to and any cookies we may have set to identify your browser session. As you use the Sites we may also attempt to automatically determine some of the demographic information previously described from the content that you elect to view.

As you use the Sites, we collect the web pages and a record of the content that you have seen. We may use this information to learn what topics and views you are interested in, and to automatically determine demographic information about you. We may use this information to enhance the services, content and advertising that we present to you.

We collect information that you submit to the Sites. This includes ratings of other content, your comments, complaints, profile information, statements, arguments, objections and commentary you enter in debate or discussion with other users and any other content that you willingly provide as you use the Sites. This content includes any forms that you may enter including text, video or audio files, graphical images, links to other sites, documents, spreadsheets or any other type of digital information you choose to provide.

We may also collect additional information about you from other sources not specifically described here. For example, you may contact our customer support department, reply to a survey or poll, or a third party could leave comments or complaints about your content on the Sites.

### 2\. Expert Verification

To protect the credibility of all our contributors and the integrity of Opposing Views, any group or individual who seeks an Opposing Views "expert" status may be asked for some personally identifiable information, possibly including current contact information, personal references, and identifying numbers for professional licenses, degrees, diplomas, honors or other third party endorsements of qualification for expert status.

We will not ask for personally identifiable information in an e-mail, nor will we send you an e-mail with a link that directs you to a page where we ask for personally identifiable information. If you receive a request that directly asks for personally identifiable information, please notify us immediately at [legal@opposingviews.com](mailto:legal@opposingviews.com).

We will ask existing and potential experts ("Experts") to contact us with personally identifiable information in order to confirm your identity, and we may be reached at:

Deep Dive Media, Llc.  
8400 Delongpre Avenue  
Los Angeles, CA 90069  

Any personally identifiable information collected from Experts will be used solely to confirm your identity and qualifications. It will not be displayed on the Sites, nor will it be transferred to any third party except for organizations or individuals under contract with Opposing Views to perform business services required for Expert qualification.

### 3\. Children and Personal Information

The sites are intended to be used by and designed for adult users, and OV does not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13 years old. If you are a parent and suspect that your child has provided OV with personally identifiable information, please contact us at [help@opposingviews.com](mailto:help@opposingviews.com).

### 4\. How We Use Personal Information

We use the information we collect to:

  * operate the Sites and publish relevant information to viewers
  * provide you with information and services you request
  * customize your experience
  * send you personalized content and promotional offers, based on your communication preferences
  * measure and improve our services
  * resolve disputes, complaints and resolve technical problems
  * conduct research
  * analyze aggregate user behavior and prepare aggregated reports
  * provide anonymous reports to internal and external clients

### 5\. Information Sharing and Disclosure

OV is not in the business of renting or selling personal information you provide on the Sites with other people or nonaffiliated companies. OV does share your information to provide products or services you've requested, when we have your permission, and under the following circumstances:

  * We may share your information with service providers under confidentiality agreements in order to help with our business operations. These companies do not have the independent right to share this information.
  * We may share names and e-mails of members who join OV as part of a co-branded partnership with OV with that specific partner.
  * We may share aggregate demographic information with third parties such as the media, advertisers, and government agencies. This aggregate information is typically in the form of statistics, such as numbers of OV users in a particular age group. Such aggregate information is not traceable back to you as an individual.
  * We may share information when required by law or under the good-faith belief that such disclosure is necessary under applicable law; to comply with legal process served upon OV; to protect the property or interests of OV; or to protect personal safety or public interests.
  * We may transfer personal information in the event that our business is sold, transferred, merged or reorganized with or into another organization.

### 6\. Public Content

Some portions of the Sites allow you to contribute ratings, reviews, comments and other content to the Sites. This content is displayed publicly to other users, OV and our partners. The content you contribute may be displayed with your OV screen name. If other members choose to, they can receive e-mail, RSS feeds, or other notifications of your new public content or publish their own content in response to yours.

We may use this public content to develop aggregate ratings, comments, reviews or other derived content for the Sites and distribution to other web sites and business partners. We may use your public content to personalize the site for you and other members and to identify and feature special content and members. For example, we may promote highly rated and regarded content on the Sites and on partner web sites.

### 7\. Cookies

OV sets and accesses cookies on your computer. A cookie is a small bit of information used by the site to track your session. It does not contain any sensitive information. No other web sites can access cookies set by OV, nor can the Sites access cookies set by other web sites.

We use third party advertising companies to serve ads and collect data on this Web site. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to OV and other websites in order to provide advertisements on this and other websites about goods and services that may be of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, [click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp).

You can block cookies by changing the settings on your browser (contact your ISP for help), but doing so may prevent you from logging in, or prevent us from delivering some of our services to you.

### 8\. Account Information and Communications

You can edit your OV Account Information at any time by logging in to the site and entering the "My OV" area.

You may opt out of receiving OV marketing materials by logging into the site, entering the My Views area and editing your email preferences. Even if you do opt out of receiving marketing materials, we reserve the right, and will continue to send you certain infrequent communications relating to the OV service and/or your account, such as service announcements and administrative messages, that are considered part of your OV account, without offering you the opportunity to opt-out of receiving them.

You can close your OV account through the "My OV" area or by contacting our customer service department at [help@opposingviews.com](mailto:help@opposingviews.com). After you close your account you will no longer receive e-mail from OV but we will retain information in order to comply with the law, prevent fraud, and continue to offer our services to other users and partners.

### 9\. Confidentiality and Security

We use electronic, physical and administrative safeguards including firewalls and advanced password protection to protect the security of your information. We limit access to personal information about you to employees who we believe reasonably need to come into contact with that information to provide products or services to you or in order to do their jobs. However, as you probably know, third parties may unlawfully intercept or access transmissions or private communications. Therefore, although we work very hard to protect your privacy, we do not promise, and you should not expect, that your personal information and private communications will always remain private.

You should take steps to protect yourself as well. For example:

  * Do not share your password with anyone else, and take measures to prevent unauthorized access or disclosure.
  * To learn more about how to protect yourself online, visit the government website [www.onguardonline.gov](http://www.onguardonline.gov/).

### 10\. Links and Third Party Sites and Ads

The Sites contains links to other web sites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content on these sites. If you have concerns about how other sites collect and use information about you, make sure to read their privacy policies.

We may allow third party advertisers to post advertisements on the Sites. These third parties may place cookies on certain pages of the Sites. We do not control those third parties, or their cookies. This privacy policy does not cover those third party advertisers’ use of cookies.

### 11\. Changes to this Privacy Policy

We may change this policy from time to time, and we will post the amended terms on the Sites. All amended terms take effect immediately for new users and 30 days after they are posted for existing members. We will notify you about significant changes in the way we treat personal information by sending a notice to the primary e-mail address specified in your OV account.

To contact us for more information about this privacy policy or how your information is treated, please contact us by email at [help@opposingviews.com](mailto:help@opposingviews.com).
